Finding Aid for North American Student Cooperative League records, 1936-1977
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
North American Student Cooperative League records 1936-1977
North American Student Cooperative League.
12.4 linear feet
85525 Bj 2
Association of student cooperative houses and stores. Administrative correspondence, collected materials from various colleges and universities; conference files, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was received jointly from the Cooperative League of the U.S.A. and the Inter-Cooperative Council of the University of Michigan (donor no. 3815 ) in several accessions beginning in 1961.
The record group is open to research.
The North American Student Cooperative League (NASCL) was founded in 1946 with the assistance of the Cooperative League of the U.S.A. Growing out of the cooperative movement begun on various college campuses in the late 1930s, NASCL was the amalgamation of several regional associations. Never a strong organization, leaders in the cooperative movement in the 1960s began stressing the need for change and redirection. A more effective organization was needed, one that would be more than a clearinghouse of information, and would instead engaged in programs of education and legislative lobbying.
In the spring of 1968, participants in a conference sponsored by the University of Michigan Inter-Cooperative Council proposed the organization of a group "for the purpose of expanding the cooperative movement across college campuses." In the fall, a group gathered in Chicago to organize the National Association of Students of Cooperation (NASCO) intended to succeed NASCL. NASCO's creation in 1968 meant that, for the first time in 20 years, student co-ops would begin working together towards their common interests.
The records of the North American Student Cooperative League cover the administration life of the organization, roughly 1946 to 1968, with scattered earlier and later materials. The records were accumulated and donated by the Inter-Cooperative Council of the University of Michigan and by the Co-operative League of the U.S.A. which at one time must have had custody of the records following the organization's demise.
The record group is organized into the following series: Correspondence; Cooperative League of the U.S.A.; Studies, surveys, and reports; Published material; Local groups (minutes and publications); Miscellaneous; Conferences; and Photographs.
Subjects:
Cooperative societies--United States.; Universities and colleges--United States.; Inter-Cooperative Council (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Cooperative societies--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
African Americans--Education.; Clothing and dress--1941-1950.; Cooperatives.; Dining rooms.; Domestic life--1941-1950.; Dormitories--1941-1950.; Interiors--1941-1950.; Kitchens--1941-1950.; Luggage.; Nursing--United States.; Students--1941-1950.; Warehouses.; Women.
Contributors:
Beall, Hayes.; Buchele, Luther.; Cooperative League of the U.S.A.; United States National Student Association.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - 1946-1947, 49 folders (Box 1)
  - 1948-February 1951, 52 folders (Box 2)
  - March 1951-1961, 55 folders (Box 3)
- Cooperative League of the U.S.A.
  - Hayes Beall (director of educational services) correspondence file
    - 1951-1959, 50 folders (Box 4)
      (annual conference records for 1954-1957 filed at end of respective years)
    - 1960-1963, 15 folders (Box 5)
  - Cooperative League of the U.S.A. correspondence on student co-ops 1941-1943 (Box 5)
- Studies, surveys, and reports
  - Executive Secretary file 1949-1951, 4 volumes (Box 5)
  - Study of Campus Co-ops by Francis E. Reilly 1936, 2 volumes (Box 5)
  - Survey of Student co-ops 1947, 1 volumes (Box 6)
  - Summary of 1949 Survey (Box 6)
  - Replies to 1952 Survey, 6 folders (Box 6)
  - Appeal to co-op wholesalers for support 1952 (Box 6)
  - Appeal to educators 1947 (Box 6)
  - Survey of Room and Board costs 1953 (Box 6)
  - Midwest co-op conference 1952 (Box 6)
  - Field Secretary reports 1952 (Box 6)
  - Field Secretary reports 1954 (Box 6)
  - Newsletter finances, 1 volumes (Box 6)
  - Financial journal 1949-1952, 1 volumes (Box 6)
  - Mailing lists, 7 folders (Box 6)
  - Young Adult Council file 1950-1954, 15 folders (Box 6)
  - Report of the U.S. Assembly of Youth, Ann Arbor 1953 (Box 6)
- Published material
  - Directory of Student Cooperative Organizations, 6 folders (Box 7)
  - N.A.S.C.L. Publications
    - Co-ops on Campus, 1944-1953, 4 folders (Box 7)
    - Co-ops in Action, 1953-1965, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Directories 1950-1952 (Box 7)
    - Newsletter 1949-1950 (Box 7)
    - Bulletins (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 7)
- Local groups (minutes and publications)
  - Midwest Federation of Campus Cooperatives 1942-1949, 10 folders (Box 7)
  - Eastern League of Campus Co-ops 1948 (Box 7)
  - Central League of Campus Co-ops undated, 1941-1957, 11 folders (Box 7)
  - Pacific Coast Students Cooperative League undated, 1939-1953, 11 folders (Box 7)
    (1939 folder includes Maccabeah Arenberg Research Report)
  - North Central Student Co-operative League 1946-1950 (Box 7)
  - North Eastern Student Cooperative League 1949-1950 (Box 8)
  - University of California at Los Angeles
    - General undated, 1937-1953, 9 folders (Box 8)
    - Newsletter 1946-1957, 10 folders (Box 8)
  - University of California (Berkeley)
    - General, undated 1939, 1944-1961, 12 folders (Box 8)
    - Newsletter
      - 1943-1949 (Box 8)
      - 1954 (Box 8)
      - 1955-1956 (Box 8)
      - 1972-1977 (Box 8)
  - Berkeley Consumers Cooperative (Box 8)
  - California Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - University of Michigan undated, 1946-1959, 8 folders (Box 8)
  - Michigan State University undated, 1945-1976, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Michigan miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - University of Washington undated, 1942-1952, 19 folders (Box 9)
  - University of Wisconsin, undated 1941-1956, 1972-1974, 8 folders (Box 9)
  - Wisconsin miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 9)
  - University of Texas, undated 1942-1957, 1975, 7 folders (Box 9)
  - Illinois miscellaneous undated, 1942-1960, 9 folders (Box 9)
  - Purdue University, undated 1947, 1952-1958, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Indiana miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - University of North Dakota 1946-1948, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Pennsylvania miscellaneous, undated 1946-1952, 1954, 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Kansas miscellaneous undated, 1946-1977, 8 folders (Box 10)
  - Oberlin College (Box 10)
  - Antioch College (Box 10)
  - Ohio miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - Nebraska miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - University of Idaho (Box 10)
  - Iowa miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - Minnesota miscellaneous undated, 1946-1953, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Missouri miscellaneous undated, 1945-1958, 7 folders (Box 10)
  - New Jersey miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - Cornell University undated, 1949-1954, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - New York miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - University of Toronto
    - General undated, 1947-1954, 3 folders (Box 10)
    - Rochdale House (Box 10)
    - Kagawa House 1946-1947, 1951-1953, 5 folders (Box 11)
  - Canada miscellaneous, 6 folders (Box 11)
  - University of Chicago 1949-1950 (Box 11)
  - University of Colorado, Boulder 1951 (Box 11)
- Miscellaneous
  - Cooperative League of the U.S.A. undated, 1936-1958, 13 folders (Box 11)
  - National Association of College Stores, 6 folders (Box 11)
  - Newspaper clippings, 5 folders (Box 11)
  - Miscellanea, 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Co-op Magazine (various issues) (Box 11)
  - The New Harbinger (various issues) (Box 11)
- Conferences
  - 1946 (Box 12)
  - 1947, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - 1948, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - 1949, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - 1949-1951 office record book (Box 12)
  - 1950, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - 1951, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - 1952, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - 1953 (Box 12)
  - 1954 (Box 12)
  - 1955 (Box 12)
  - 1956 (Box 12)
  - 1957 (Box 12)
- Photographs
  - Colleges and universities
    - Baker (Box 13)
    - California-Berkeley (Box 13)
    - California-Los Angeles (Box 13)
    - Chicago (Box 13)
    - Cornell (Box 13)
    - Georgia State (Box 13)
    - Idaho (Box 13)
    - Indiana Central (Box 13)
    - Iowa (Box 13)
    - Michigan (Box 13)
    - Minnesota (Box 13)
    - Missouri (Box 13)
    - Nebraska (Box 13)
    - Oberlin (Box 13)
    - Oregon (Box 13)
    - Penn State (Box 13)
    - Purdue (Box 13)
    - Syracuse (Box 13)
    - Texas (Box 13)
    - Toronto (Box 13)
    - Washington (Box 13)
    - Wisconsin (Box 13)
  - Annual conference
    - 1946 (Box 13)
    - 1947 (Box 13)
    - 1949 (Box 13)
    - 1952 (Box 13)
    - 1954 (Box 13)
    - 1955 (Box 13)
    - 1957 (Box 13)
  - Groups
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
    - Unidentified (Box 13)
  - Individuals
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
    - Unidentified (Box 13)
  - Midwest Federation of Campus Coops (Box 13)
  - National Cooperative Refinery Association (Box 13)
  - Pacific Coast Students' Cooperative League (Box 13)